

#### **ABOUT ME**

Mechanical engineer with 2.5 year of expereince in Fininte Element Analysis and Machine learning with proficiency in Engineering simulations and Data Visualization, Machine learning model fitting and Automation using python. In current organization Embeded cutting edge Al solutions in FE Analysis along with automation, there by improving the productivity by 30%.

#### LINKS

#### Website:

https://medium.com/@nityanandhiremath7

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Received ON-Fly Award in current organization
- Secured a score of 366 in GATE ME 2018
- Prepared and Participated Eco-KART in national event held in NOYDA

# NITYANANDA HIREMATH

**ENGINEE** 



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **QUEST GLOBAL**

Bengaluru Oct 2021 - Present

#### Engineer

- Client: IHI Aero Japan
- Completed 20 task till date with on-time delivery of 90% with quality of 94%.
- Carried out Hex meshing for LPT Blades, followed by Structural, Modal and Creep analysis for various stage and load conditions.
- Implemented cross platform connection between ANSYS and Python using PYANSIS. Created AI based Regression model to predict Temperature and pressure distribution. Prepared APDL scripts for various analysis for quick and accurate results.
- Blade defect detection using image recoganization using CNN.
- Preparation of automation scripts for report preparation with Python 3.7 and ANSYS APDL.
- Handled weekly Japanese customer meeting with good feedback.

#### SNAPBIZZ CLOUDTECH PVT LTD

Bengaluru Nov 2020 - Oct 2021

# ML Intern

- Developed web scraping scripts which replaced 210 hr man hours for a week.
- Developed dynamic price guessing ML model and successfully deployed in AWS. Developed data cleaning and validation scripts using python replaced 50hr man hour for a weak.

# ACE DESIGNERS

Bengaluru Jul 2019 - Jul 2020

#### Post graduate Intern

- Carried out research on Machine tool components design, analysis and FE model updating methods.
- Developed Stiffness and mass matrix reduction scripts for model order reduction. Successfully carried out modal results comparison between FE model and experimental results using MAC method to find the differences.
- Implemented FE model updating method for boring bar based on experimental results.

#### **EDUCATION**

# BMS COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

Bengaluru 2020

#### KLE TECH UNIVERSITY

UNIVERSI Hubli 2017

#### Master's Degree

In Machine Design with CGPA of 8.9

#### Bachelor of Technology

In Automobile with CGPA of 8.56

# **SKILLS**

PRO-E (CAD)

**HYPERMESH** 

ANSYS

PYTHON

MACHINE LEARNING

DEEP LEARNING

AWS

DATA ANALYSIS

## **PUBLICATIONS**

SCHOLARLY ARTICLES FOR FINITE ELEMENT MODEL UPDATING OF MACHINE TOOL BORING BAR AND DETERMINATION OF CHATTER STABILITY SCIENCE DIRECT NOV 2020

### **COURSES**

EDX Hands on experience in Engineering Simulations
Mar 2021

UDAMY
Mar 2021

Learn complete python in simple way

NPTEL Computational fluid dynamic

'Machine learning with python master class

#### HOBBIES

Apr 2020

**UDAMY** 

Jun 2021

PHOTOGRAPHY, PORTRAIT SKETCHING, PLAYING TABALA, TRAVELLING, COOKING